KATHLEEN MERCADO

201-978-8617 | kathleenmerc@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathleenmercado | https://github.com/kathleenmerc

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven by a passion for emerging technologies and lifelong learning, I am actively pursuing an entry-level software developer role. With 5+ years of healthcare experience, I bring a unique perspective and valuable skills in problem-solving, analytical thinking, attention to detail, and effective communication. Committed to collaboration, excellence, and constant growth, I am eager to join a team that shares these values, where I can apply my knowledge and expertise to make a meaningful impact.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front-End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Vanilla JS, ES6), TypeScript, React JS, Next JS, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, WordPress, Figma, DOM Manipulation
- Back-End: Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB, Google Firebase & Firestore, REST APIs, Object Oriented Programming
- Version Control: Git, GitHub, Gitpod, Visual Studio Code
- Additional Tools: Electronic Medical Records (EMR/EHR), Google Workspace, Microsoft Office, Trello

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Web Application - Recipe Finder: Deployed site | GitHub

- Solo project | JavaScript, React, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, CSS3, JSON Web Token
- Designed and developed a full-stack web application to help users search for recipes based on ingredients they already have in their kitchen. Users can securely sign up and log in to their accounts, search for recipes, add recipes to their favorites page, and keep track of what recipes they've cooked.
- Built using the MERN stack and features full CRUD operations, JWT user authentication with bcrypt, HTTP requests, and React hooks.

2D Game - The Helicopter Game: Deployed site | GitHub

- Solo project | HTML5, HTML Canvas, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript
- Recreated the classic Helicopter Game with new features such as 1 or 2-player modes, player lives, and high score functionality.
- Included use of classes, objects, DOM manipulation, local storage, event listeners, and flexbox.

Mobile Application - TherapEase: GitHub

- Team project | TypeScript, Next.js, Google Firebase & Firestore, TailwindCSS, Figma
- Collaborated with a team of 4 developers to create an app to enhance the appointment scheduling process for patients and physical therapists.
- Implemented Agile work methodologies and pair programming using tools such as Trello, Discord, and VS Code Live Share to produce efficient project management and team collaboration.
- Created user stories and low fidelity wireframes on Figma to align best with user needs.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer (Contract) | *Nexus Technologies Group, LLC.*

March 2023 – April 2023

- Designed and built a WordPress website for a Jamaican restaurant, while coordinating with the client to understand project specifications, integrate their brand voice, and successfully meet their launch timeline.
- Collaborated with a team of 3 web developers to create a responsive website with optimized UX/UI, aiming to generate an increase in website traffic and online orders.
- Streamlined communication and collaboration by utilizing Microsoft Teams and optimized project organization and workflow efficiency using Trello.

Physical Therapist | *Ivy Rehab Physical Therapy & Pivot Physical Therapy*

Nov 2018 - Oct 2021

Utilized data analysis and interpretation to track patient progress, identify trends, and make data-driven decisions
that led to a 25% reduction in treatment duration and readmission rates.

- Adapted quickly to new technologies and software platforms within the healthcare industry, displaying a strong
 aptitude for learning new technical skills, reducing administrative time by 25%, and improving overall workflow
 efficiency.
- Applied problem-solving skills to develop tailored treatment plans for diverse patient populations, demonstrating analytical thinking and attention to detail, resulting in overall improvements in patient outcomes and retention.

EDUCATION

Per Scholas | Computer Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp

Sept 2022 - Jan 2023

• Successfully completed a full stack software development program, achieving a 99.63% final grade, where I gained proficiency in the MERN stack, JavaScript, and computer science concepts.

Design Lab | *UX Foundations: Visual and UI Design Course for Beginners*

May 2022 - Aug 2022

• Designed responsive screens, icons, and logos in Figma incorporating visual design elements, user interface design principles, empathy for users, and user accessibility concepts with the goal of optimizing user experience.

Northeastern University | Boston, MA

- Doctor of Physical Therapy (DPT)
- Bachelor of Science (BS) in Rehabilitation Science, Cum Laude